Mohammad S. Rezaie

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Creative, detail-oriented, software engineer with a deep interest in back-end development and AI. Experienced in developing and deploying successful front and back-end web applications. Excited in collaborating with a team of talented developers and bringing my skills to a tech company with global reach.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at 100devs, Los Angeles, CA

March 2023 — Present

- Collaborated with a team of developers to build modern and responsive web applications using best practices
- Built semantically structured full stack web applications
- Applied agile methodologies like SCRUM for project management

Software Developer Intern at E-Spot | Kabul, Afghanistan

June 2021 — August 2021

Developed a cashless payment system aimed to reduce the need for paper money transactions for businesses and clients improving the efficiency and efficacy of transactions with the use of rechargeable RFID cards.

Freelance Full-stack Developer | Kabul, Afghanistan

April 2020 — Present

Created full stack web applications and static websites for different clients across small and medium size businesses. Notable clients:

<u>AYAT Clothing Shop (Full-stack Web App)</u> – Users can access the web app and find their favorite clothing designs, get information about the team of designers, get the latest news about the business and contact the shop owners.

VOLUNTEERING

Volunteer Help Desk Support Technician | Fort Dix, NJ

October 2021 — November 2021

Assisted in the establishment of a community center for newly arriving Afghan guests to the US. Created an online reservation system for guests to rent laptops, and preparing and configuring over 50+ laptop to be used by guests.

RECENT PROJECTS

<u>Textual Cryptography (Full-stack Web App)</u> – This web app allows users to encrypt and decrypt text messages using various modern and robust encryption algorithms.

<u>Personal Portfolio (Full-stack Web App)</u> – My personal web app showcasing my skills and background and the coding projects that I have done so far and the ones that I am working on.

<u>Star-Wars Wiki (API Front-end)</u> – The app allows users to explore and retrieve various information about the Star Wars universe. It is implemented using JavaScript and asynchronous programming techniques.

Other Projects: Home Services – mobile app for recruiting expertise, UniProg – university progress tracker, and many more.

CONTACT

+1 804-350-1722

msulaymanr@outlook.com

msrezaie.pythonanywhere.com

github.com/msrezaie

linkedin.com/in/msrezaie

SKILLS

HTML

CSS

Bootstrap

JavaScript

Node.js

Express.js

Python

Django

API

SQL

Git

EDUCATION

American University of Afghanistan

2018 - 2023

Major: Software Engineering

LANGUAGES

Persian (Native)

English (Fluent)